Michael Nicholas

Junior Product Manager

9	61 Cedar Avenue, Rockville Centre, NY 11570
Ç,	(516) 459 3414

michaelrvc@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/michael-nicholas-0620/
https://github.com/MichaelNicholas1
michaelnicholas1 github io

Career Objective

Product design and management professional: Graduated Summa Cum Laude from the University at Albany with a degree in Computer Science and completed the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate. Exhibits expertise over a multitude of technical areas, including data-manipulation and visualization through spreadsheets, R/RStudio, and MySQL, UI/UX wireframing and prototyping in Figma, and roadmap management in Azure Devops. Strives to translate these hard skills, natural leadership, and communication prowess to elevate teams to new heights through promoting data-driven decision-making and agile product management values and principles.

Experience

SocialLadder, Remote Junior Product Manager (Roadmap Manager and Feature Designer)

March 2022 - PRESENT

- Contributes to all stages of the product life cycle for <u>SocialLadder</u>, a SaaS brand ambassador management platform, for both their web and mobile ambassador experiences, as well as their web admin portal.
- Drives product vision into delivery, including initial business design and documentation, user stories, and ideation, overseeing technical development and roadmapping of both internal and international teams in daily standups, and launch + post-release analysis and communication, all by collaborating with cross-functional teams, including product support and integration,, product specialists, account managers, developers, and stakeholders.

IdeasFWD, Remote Lead Product and Technical Intern

January 2021 - Feb 2022

- Lead the product analysis, research, and technical division at <u>IdeasFWD</u>, a small start-up company by helping design and build the foundation for a mobile, creativity- focused insights gathering social media platform called WeCreatives.
- Handled data analytics and visualization, application prototyping, mockups, and wireframing using Figma, weekly agile sprint structure, task delegation / management, and operates as business liaison in presenting completed deliverables

Beemo, FH Münster Software Engineer Intern, Ubiquitous Computing and Human-Computer Interaction

March 2020 - April 2020

- Worked on a small, international scrum team of software engineers in Germany to learn about and develop various projects through the UAS7 internship study program via collaboration with Beemo software engineering laboratory
- Applied an adaptable mindset towards new technologies, in particular by learning Angular, towards updating the driver window for FischerTechnik, a brand of construction toys used to teach about engineering principles and simple machines

Education

Google, Data Analytics Professional Certificate

June 2021 - August 2021 - Completed an extensive job-ready Google Career training program that focused on bolstering proficiency in existing technical spaces such as data cleaning, visualization, and project management, while also learning how to interpret and transform complex data into actionable and clear insights.

University at Albany, State University of New York, Albany, NY Bachelor of Arts in Computer Science, Minors in Business and Informatics - August 2016 - May 2020 - GPA: 3.820

Relevant Projects

- Developed a bootstrapped personal portfolio web-hosted on GitHub, using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, found at https://michaelnicholasl.github.io
- Personal PHP project web hosted on Heroku to plot out player-character mastery data using Riot Game's developer API for their game "League of Legends", including sortable and togglable information and storing user data within a MySQL database
- Competitive, fast-paced senior group project to create a next generation asset portfolio management application titled "TradeX" with new deliverables tacked on as time progresses; with bidding to impress "consumer" at intermittent stages.

Awards

- Dean's List August 2016 May 2020
- Presidential Scholarship August 2016 May 2020
- Honors College at University at Albany August 2016 May 2018